Lower ROI.
Agents aren't stupid.
They're just blind.
It's going to choose the completely wrong schema for the data.
It's going to infer a relationship that doesn't exist because while it's
saving you money
in terms of human interactions, and it's saving you money in terms of hours
burnt on business processes and operations, it's killing you in data.
So how do we fix it?
Hi, everybody. I am Tom.
I run a little company called Streambased,
and everyone knows that every single great meetup
talk starts with a bunch of apologies.
So I'm going to get all of those out of the way straight away.
And the first one: anyone here at Big Data London last week?
That's the best thing I've ever seen in my life.
They are.
It links into the next apology.
But I'm a data guy.
I'm not necessarily an AI guy. So,
there are no data guys in the room.
Do you know the last time I was in a room with no data?
Guys. It's good.
Derek, you've ruined it.
Have you done? What are you doing to me? So.
But anyway, that's the first apology.
If you were at Big Data London, you might have seen big chunks of this talk before.
And it kind of links into the message that I'm about to give you. Last week,
I was approaching this from the angle of data engineers,
data product people and platform engineers.
And this week I'm approaching it from AI, ML engineers
in the same process and the same principles still apply.
It's kind of interesting.
The second one I kind of already covered: I'm not an AI guy that much.
I'm a coding agent user.
This will have no coding agents in it.
But what's interesting about it is that, I was watching Rob's talk
and we've got a lot of the same principles. We actually haven't correlated
or done anything like that, but still, it's all good. So,
with that in mind,
let's have a
let's have a quick poll, I think,
I'm not like I said, I'm not going to be talking about coding agents.
I'm not going to be talking about refining how you deliver AI
in your day to day life and you're working world.
How many of you guys are actually running agents in production?
Maybe it's the room,
but that is double what I've seen previously.
That's great. Your hands up, guys. Get your hands on hands like it?
It's very, really important of those guys.
How many of you guys
have a dedicated set of data sources?
A dedicated set of data sets that power those agents hands?
None of them drops. Cool.
All right, in that case, all of you guys must know a data engineer.
Yes. How's that relationship?
That fun?
I'll ask the question in a different way.
Keep.
Keep your hands up if you think you have every single piece of data that you need.
I didn't even have to bother.
I know no one put their hand back up.
I didn't even have to bother. Okay. That good? That's good.
That means I'm talking to the right crowd.
Great.
So the other thing that every AI.
Well, that's bright.
The other thing that every AI
focus talks that you have to start starts with the state of AI.
I'm not going to do that. Don't worry.
A, I'm not qualified to talk about the state of AI.
But, be like, I don't think the state of AI is going crazy at the moment,
but I do want to go back to a little bit of history,
and I want to keep that history data focused, because I'm
trying to do a hearts and minds job on you tonight, calling that up front.
And I'm trying to get you to think
differently about the way you look at the data that powers your agents.
And I think history tells us where why we need to do that.
So we go all the way back as a world.
I'm going to talk about chatbots primarily because.
Why not?
I think we go back to: cool trick.
Great. I can make it.
That looks just like a human. Fantastic. That fairly quickly migrated to
I can do some actual things here.
And I'd say number two is probably where I'd count as RAG starting to come in.
I have a love-hate history with RAG, as I'm
sure you all do, but yeah.
And then it's only really. But I don't
consider people going to throw things at me.
I don't consider RAG to be thinking about data.
Seriously.
But yes.
So I consider sort of MCP to a
these are the times when we're starting to think about,
giving
reasonable data to our agents so that they can perform
a customer facing function.
That escalated quickly.
So we went from
kind of interesting to everyone has an MCP server.
You can now every literally anything you want to do.
You can order pizza via MCP now. Right.
It's it's just become a de facto thing that if you're making any kind
of software product or working with any kind of data you need to offer
or able to take any kind of actions, you need to offer an interface to this,
and that's gone.
Okay. Let's say.
But what I think we're swinging back round to now
is just exposing everything is not the answer.
We need to start thinking sensibly about how we work with data
and how we supply it to AI systems.
And because when you think about it, an AI system
with a set of data connections is really a little microcosm of reality.
And that's what you're creating here.
And you control what is available in that reality.
You control the view that you see, and that is going to have drastic effects
and the capabilities of that reality,
but also the cost and return on investment.
So I'm going to talk to you about blind spots,
and it's hard to get much simpler of a blind spot than this.
I'm sure every single one of
you saw this back in the early days of going like, we have a model.
It's trained on a big bunch of data. That was a long time ago.
If I ask you a question today, it's going to give me a bad answer.
So this is the very, very the classic mode. And,
it's actually a really, really good example
because in this example this is entirely made up by the way.
But in this example at least it's caught it and at least it's giving you a note.
I know a bunch of models that didn't do that
and just gave you the same weather for today over and over and over again.
That's something more return to you later.
But it's the example of a blind spot. Is,
an agent
making a decision to provide you with an answer?
I don't necessarily want to say hallucinating it because it's
there's some new answers to it.
To provide you an answer based on outdated or inaccurate
or non-existent data that's there.
It doesn't always have to be this obvious, right?
They come in a variety of forms.
I'm going to give you three more,
because you always like to find the funny stories from the
from the depths of early AI.
Just missing data
and out of date data is not the only blind spot you can have.
Much more common one that we're starting to see everywhere at the moment is wrong.
Scoping or over scoping data.
Yeah, this famously happened.
An agent deployed by a Chevy dealership,
but you asked it what a good mid-range car was and it tried to sell you a Tesla.
That that happens.
But then on the same kind of bounce, how many times
have we been there and gone?
Oh, look, somebody deployed a chatbot.
It's actually just a wrapper.
And I can ask it to do anything I want.
And it will just go ahead and do it and burn through their tokens
rather than mine.
That's a that's a real security problem.
That's everywhere at the moment.
And so yeah, another obvious one.
But we can move on and we can find even more subtle ones.
Missing relationships is the most underappreciated problem
with data in agentic AI, in my opinion, today.
So we have an internal agent.
It's meant to help me.
It's meant to make my job better.
But it doesn't understand the relationships between two different
departments, two different pieces of two different products or something like that.
By missing that relationship context,
it's not able to give good and accurate answers.
So in this case, it's gone ahead and said, look, Acme is a prime, prime
potential customer for our cloud products.
We're going to sell them a million a year
ARR. They're already burning $12 million a year on our on-prem product,
and we're just going to eat ourselves doing this.
But it's a it's a data blind spot that's causing this.
And then finally unknown doesn't exist.
There is a very big difference between no data and unknown data.
Right.
So this one's textbook does do you have any support issues right now
depending on what which what path the agent is going to take to fetch
the data, it can report no confidently and accurately by going through
everything you've defined in your skill by hitting every single.
But because of a data blind spot, it's completely incorrect.
Answer.
So how are they going to know when they don't have the access they don't have?
When they don't have the information they need to answer the question?
I like to include the third one, by the way,
because we're always comparing these to human like experiences.
And humans are fantastic at this.
This is an area where the machines really need to start catching up.
But humans are greater going.
There's no really mean.
No, I guess we're all skeptical, paranoid people underneath.
Does no really mean no?
Or does it mean some kind of unknown state that I then need to investigate further?
This is teaching a grandma
how to suck eggs for you guys, but there's really three ways of getting.
I'm going to do it very fast.
There's really three ways of getting data to our agents today.
RAG is best for large
corpora of static or at least slow-moving data.
It's great for narrowing stuff down.
I like to think of it as doing the test with the textbook open.
Right?
But it's not.
I don't feel like it's a a worth a usable framework
for being able to do live up to the minute data and for being able to do
intense operations that you can then take actions over.
If it was, we wouldn't have invented MCP.
We did great for this kind of stuff. So
set of tools,
access your database, access your APIs.
And it's brilliant for being able
to get hold of fresh, wide scope data
from essentially any task.
It's because of that, it's a bit like the Wild West out
there, like it's just a connect, connect, connect, connect connect.
Hit anything you like, make the decisions later. My,
my favorite sort of MCP story is
you connect your agent to every MCP in the world,
and it makes bad decisions because it's got super multiple.
It's got multiple representations of the same data.
Right. So what do you do?
And the most common one I see is,
well, we make a much narrower scoped agent.
That's what we do.
We connect less than we make an expert at each one of those.
Then we create a multi-agent system around that that just introduces
all the same problems back again.
And you end up pushing everything up into the agent orchestration layer,
which becomes incredibly complex, very, very fast.
And then finally we got skills.
I mentioned skills because really one of these,
one of the steps or that one of the things you define inside skills
could be fetching data as a data fetching mechanism.
It's not really that skills are meant to define
repeatable tasks and repeatable steps within repeatable tasks.
They're not really designed for direct access to data.
So one step could be.
And this is the end result.
So really we've MCP is what we're going to end up
talking about because it's the one that directly access the data.
But what I was just mentioning about the free for all across
all the systems, it's a very different world from what me
as a data engineer and a data systems designer would see on the left
hand side versus the world we've kind of accidentally fallen into
on the right hand side.
What was
really, really good good about the the left hand
side world was that you had like a 1 to 1 problem solution.
Well, you had a very well defined stakeholder.
You had a very well defined problem, and you designed a data set
that would solve it.
Anybody who has done data
engineering will understand the concept of the medallion architecture.
You have bronze tables that are essentially
your raw data, just massive and, a big mess.
Silver are cleaned, filtered
gold are very, very business oriented.
So these would be aggregates and things that you could directly show
to your business stakeholders.
And that was a world we worked in for for four decades
easily probably longer than that now. Right.
And it made a lot of sense.
And we've suddenly been dumped into this other side and to be honest,
Have some sympathy for us guys
As data engineers whistle, what really gets the world
became hard in in a world.
Any question, any time for any stakeholder in any area
has to be managed and has to be handled. So
I'll skip I'll
skip ahead a little bit and say, what I'm going to ask you to do
is a be nice to your data engineers, but B if you could just ask them
to have it change the way they think a little bit about how they look at data
according to the new requirements, okay,
because most of the poor data, overworked data engineers I see at the moment
are trying desperately to continue building this for agentic AI,
and it's going to kill them.
Poor things.
So we said we had
MCP and MCP is great, but it answers
a connectivity problem only it doesn't do all of the good stuff
that typically goes under traditional data ETL.
So as you traverse from bronze
to gold, well, you're going to see is you're going to
introduce business, meaning you're going to guarantee freshness
to a certain cadence, you're going to guarantee correctness, and you're going
to produce do verification to ensure that that's the case.
And you're also going to answer the the next question
that people aren't asking yet about whether your budget can actually sustain
these kind of operations.
It was very interesting to hear what Rob was saying about metrics and costing,
and about how I got the impression
that it was quite difficult to put dollar values,
on these kinds of costs and business value with data.
It's easy.
We've been doing it for decades and decades.
They are very,
very tightly controlled budgets with very tightly controlled targets.
And and you can do predictions and estimations.
There's tools everywhere to do it.
So the cost of an agent going after
doing large scans on your Iceberg tables or in your in your data
warehouses, in your data lake is very, very measurable and very significant.
And I think we're just starting to learn that,
especially if it does it for every single prompt.
So we really need something extra.
One caveat on this.
It is possible to build all four of these into MCP.
Of course it is.
No one does, but it is possible to do it right if you want to do and customize
everything to your business goals and your business needs, great, go for it.
Not seen it yet?
Please someone do it and prove me wrong.
So normally
at this point... where's the fluffy mic?
No, no. It's fine. No, no, it's not that I don't need it.
But normally at this point someone's put their hand up and said, okay,
the answer to all AI problems is more AI, of course.
So why can't we just have smarter agents?
Why can't they make better choices?
Why can't we move the world of data engineering into the agentic world?
I'm going to say
today that we can't do that, not forever.
It was only a about a year and a half ago
that I was saying, don't trust your LLMs to write SQL.
They're no good at it.
Turns out they're really freaking good at it now.
So you could pick any one of the major models
and you could trust it to all day long now.
So maybe in some time we will end up with much smarter agents
that can handle the likes of arbitration, completeness, provenance
and they will be able to make smart decisions about data sources.
Today, if I gave you something like this very contrived example,
and gave you three different versions of the world,
which you will have because physics means you will have it like data moves slowly
through many systems as it ages, and you will get a different answer
from each system.
I did this
slide used to have some examples of when I set this up.
It's not even a case of it choosing one.
You can trace this back and see the MCP calls.
In a lot of cases it won't even check.
It'll make a decision about it, won't even check all three.
It'll make a decision about which one's the correct one.
Just give you an answer.
And again it will blindly trust with 100% confidence.
You got that answer.
So yeah conflicts are a fact of life.
And we we could put smarter agents in to deal with it.
But I'm going to propose something different.
And yes, LLMs are terrible data engineers.
That five step process is something that you must do
pretty much every single prompt.
If it's going to work with any kind of data infrastructure of any significant
size, and it's not very good at any one of those things.
And yet
when you start talking about
using them as data engineers or, or really
when you start talking about and data, the orange box is where everybody starts.
They just go, yeah, context sizes.
Yeah. Too much data in the context.
It's actually not this is the minor thing right at the end.
The fact that it's going to choose the completely wrong schema for the data,
it's going to infer a relationship that doesn't exist.
It's going to resolve a conflict by choosing the
by arbitrating the incorrect system and ranking it incorrectly.
It's going to fail to enforce a privacy policy that would say
you would had implied between your bronze and silver layers,
it's just going to skip over that, and then it's going to access
your data systems in the most efficient way possible.
And like I don't yeah I know, it's like everybody see this.
Like, how do you do SELECT * WHERE name equals Tom?
What do you do.
You SELECT *, put all of that into the context window, and then
And then we go through and filter everything like that.
Right. Yeah.
We've all seen that.
We've all seen examples of things like that. And we are.
So if you want to talk about return on investment for
agentic systems as a whole,
This is a major thing you need to consider.
Because while it's saving you money in terms of human interactions,
and it's saving you money in terms of hours burnt on, business
processes and operations, it's killing you in data.
So how do we fix it?
This is the bit.
This is the slide to start showing to your data engineers.
So we need to start stop thinking about
1 to 1 problem mappings.
We need to start stop thinking about graceful aging of data
through bronze silver, gold when need stop thinking about,
your data sets as business focused
and narrowly scoped by the time they reach the end of their ETL flows.
Instead, I'm.
What you need to start thinking about is context.
I don't mean the context window,
but I want to think like there are no good words to say this right?
I thought fabric was nice.
No, Microsoft has had that.
And like, yeah, all of the nice words that mean a consistent data layer
have all been taken. So I'm reusing context for a minute.
But you want to start
thinking about creating
larger data sets that preserve optionality for the agent.
That means we start designing data, we start designing the data sets,
and we start designing the data interfaces in ways in which the don't
close off options and are built to answer multiple questions and start
and to to go in different ways rather than to go otherwise.
AI-centric data warehouse?
At this. Yeah.
The question was for the live stream.
Is this an AI-centric data warehouse?
I have played this game before.
Absolutely it is.
Yes, absolutely it is.
But as we go to the next slide, it might be an AI-
centric data warehouse and many other things.
We'll we go for a principle rather than a technology.
Where does the graph fit into the equation here?
So I'm going to duck out
and sort of say your knowledge graph is sort of your RAG style stuff.
Right?
It's not as graph is a very,
very powerful way to design this bottom line.
Right? It's a great way of doing it.
Not all data, in fact, primarily,
not all data fits it well.
And in fact, the primary cases that you're probably
using agentic AI for right now doesn't fit it well.
So if you're looking up flight orders, you're doing things like that knowledge
graph don't don't match that data set very, very well.
What does and what has
for 40 years again is SQL right.
It does.
If we just go back down SQL.
It's a the reason it never dies is because it's really, really good
at expressing the kind of problems that we want to solve.
So I think a knowledge graph again, I, I, I,
I always associate it back
with the kind of RAG principle of this is a great way of finding
a, of narrowing a large corpus of static or slow moving data.
But if you want to do something highly interactive, it's,
it's it's very difficult to manage.
I'd. I'll repeat it that way.
Okay.
You said the problem with the LLMs and the data analysis is because the context
is really like it's not enough, so the data wouldn't fit in there.
But if you.
Sorry, if you.
As a human were given a database, a million of rows,
you wouldn't be reading every single row by yourself.
You would just be analyzing the patterns between all these rows.
So that's the same essentially.
So it doesn't need to have all the million rows in its context.
Absolutely.
That's a 100% agree.
That's the way it should work.
But there's a missing.
There's a missing step where it's aware of the date of data,
shape and data meaning and data intent
and the capabilities of the system that it's working with,
so that it can push those filters down so that it can push the things
down to the place where they're most efficient.
As humans, we understand that. Great, right?
You're not going to like you're not going to sit there and go, oh,
I have every single I don't know, what are we going for?
The odds
on every single football match that's ever been played over the last 50 years.
Let's stick it in Excel and go line by line. Right.
I have seen LLMs make
similar decisions like that and decide that is the best way to do it,
just simply because they're not aware that there was an alternative.
Which is why I did the cop out and said,
today, tomorrow,
we'll see where we're going.
And it kind of plays into this,
describe don't just transform.
One of the things that I think is completely missing
Anyone here aware of OpenMetadata?
Oh, there we go.
One of the things I think is completely missing.
I had RAG, MCP, skills.
I think like a semantic model is like a unified
a way of providing a semantic model to AI is still completely missing. Open
Metadata is a great project that is trying to do this.
Go check it out on GitHub.
It's wonderful.
So yeah, I think we can do an example.
So yeah, this slide just says if you wanted to do it
the old way, you'd have to go around, you'd have to build something specific.
But the new way is about taking a step back and going.
I'm building for context rather than building for business problem.
What I see at the moment.
Yes, is why
I ask you to be gentle to the data engineers is they just build more of this.
The answer to turning things blue is not building
more orange.
So how do we do it?
Luckily for us, we've had the tools for decades.
We've been ready, and as a data engineers and platform engineers,
we know how to do this.
The concept of federation preserves optionality by default.
So by federation, I mean, if you want to issue a query across a
one single query, can map to multiple data sets, multiple data
systems, and provide one logical service.
So we could federate.
I've given Iceberg, Kafka and a CRM, but imagine everything: APIs,
your systems, whatever you want down here, all of your data sources.
What you do is you delay the materialization, you delay the,
fetching and aggregating and location,
and you push things as far left in the architecture diagram as you can go.
So federation then lends itself to views.
Again, these are not ahead of time things.
These are not a things you have to need to continually maintain.
These are things we can take advantage on the fly and preserve that optionality.
And in that way, we are able to allow our agents
to work with a broader context rather than some,
some very specifically defined define things.
I'll leave you to read the
rest of the boxes a bit later, because I like questions about,
let's do a concrete example.
I actually hate this slide.
I had a much simpler version of it, but it's it.
But it is, if you squint a little bit, a concrete example of this kind of problem.
The easiest way to explain the federation and view approach
is by looking at something we call temporal consistency.
So it's just time you have a real-time system such as Apache Kafka.
Big Kafka fan here, that is built to manage data that runs from the last
a millisecond ago all the way back to three, four, seven days.
But that's it. That's it's cut off. That's its time window.
During that time, traditionally, you would have had a job
that would have taken the data out of Kafka,
moved it across and placed it into some long term storage store
place something that your warehouse, your your lake.
So things like Apache Iceberg.
We love Apache Iceberg, right?
That's the traditional approach.
But it's not.
But it forces the LLM to make a decision.
Right.
In order to be able to solve the problems it's got it's
got to fetch from both systems, and it's got to do the stitching together.
Instead, we can put this context layer in the middle
and do the stitching as data engineers ourselves and present a logical,
full view that goes from one millisecond
to go all the way back to five years.
That's the example. With time.
There are examples with many, many other dimensions
and many other ways of doing it.
But this is the principle I want you to take away.
Let's federate across multiple systems to build these logical views
that are ready for consumption.
And the one pitch
slide, coincidentally: that's what we do at Streambased.
You knew this was coming.
So we stitch real-time and lake systems together.
And we offer a unified governance context that you can then use with your agents.
Yeah.
Please all take a photo of that and show it to your data team.
That's all I got to ask.
That's your homework for today.
And it wouldn't
be an ROI slide if we didn't show where you get ROI.
So as you can see on the left hand side, what we've done is
we've logically created a set of layers
that are infinitely consumable by our agentic systems.
So we've given it a full history.
We've given it completely fresh data.
We've given it a semantic model that it can
then use to infer relationships and intent.
And we've given it consistent definitions.
We've added governance and policies.
And we built up this layer specifically for ingestion via,
our agents.
And it allows you to do a lot of really cool stuff.
So in terms of better decisions, I don't even just want to limit it
to better decisions.
You could say more accurate data, but more scope is the most important thing.
You can reliably allow your
agent to go off and hit multiple systems
and answer questions that were way beyond the scope
it was designed for.
You can also automate much better.
You need less human review because you've designed the consistency
in at the bottom layer, rather than add it at the top
of my,
my pet hate at the moment
is that you solve this problem via.
I've seen a bunch of people solve this problem via multi-agent systems,
which means it's fetch, fetch fetch fetch fetch, reconcile.
It's got to be the most expensive and time consuming way of doing it right?
When, with a little bit of thought of designing at the bottom layer,
you can avoid most of that cost.
And most of that time I do it.
I liken it to say you can get the right item out of a vending machine
by smashing every single button until the right thing comes out right.
If you do it fast enough, you won't even notice.
But is it the most efficient and is it the best ROI for that?
For your experience with the vending machine? Probably not.
And then I don't need to tell you about cost, right?
Cost is a simple and well, well recorded.
Ask your data engineers about the cost metrics they have.
They have lots.
It stops them going away,
doing unnecessary operations on data.
It's shrinks your context windows
because we're able to push a lot of the work down into the data layer.
And it gets you.
And because of that, you also get faster responses.
Last slide I promise.
So, lower ROI.
This is a very, very emotive... this is the marketing department
Slide.
Lower ROI. Agents aren't stupid, they're just blind.
If we if we need to take a data focus as we you don't have a choice.
We are taking a data focus in the way we build agentic systems.
Now, then we need to make data more available, more visible,
make its meaning explicit, and give the agent only what it needs
and the ability to to push down
what it needs and into the data layer so that it doesn't fetch everything.
And I'm done.
Thanks very much.
So are you alluding to stream-based data
sent to your agents and filtered by context?
Is that is that where your your product is also going towards?
If you wanted to use the Streambased MCP server, then
that would be an excellent idea.
I think other products are available.
So yes, I am.
This is the the world we live in.
But as you probably understood from the presentation
I'm trying to champion a principle rather than the product here.
There are plenty of ways to achieve this.
Streambased is one that's particularly focused on real-time context,
and if you don't have a need for real-time
context, you don't have the need for Streambased.
But the principle of federation and logical view building still applies.
So. So the hardest two hard tasks here are filtering and culling, right?
How do you make sure that you filter and how do you make sure you cull so that you
don't, you know, carry on the same thing in your next interaction?
Yeah. So,
the tools for
filtering in on the fly have existed, and data systems
or performant enough to be able to do them for a long time.
However,
I did this talk at Big Data London
and it was literally saying why AI is killing ETL.
That was my pitch, across it.
And that was to a room full of data engineer.
So that went down really well.
But yeah.
And there's a slide missing from this version of the deck
that says it doesn't kill completely those silver and gold data set.
They just have to be really, really useful in order to find a place in the world.
So where the old way was to go, start from that principle right at the beginning.
So we start from the fact that we're building something for a specific problem.
This we need to reverse that and zoom out of that and go.
We're building for a whole wide range of problems.
We're trying to build a consistent context.
Sometimes we might build something more specific
as a performance optimization or as a cost optimization.
So it's about switching the way we think about it rather than anything else
that.
In regulated environments,
when it comes to data, the compliance and auditing is very important.
And now in the solution, actually we are just consolidated, consolidating
every data platform under one view.
Considering that some of the data points,
a few of them have different kind of permission level.
For example, the documents one.
Maybe some of them should only be visible at the C-level or above.
So how can you make sure that this view,
that kind of compliance are,
addressed?
Yeah, it's it's the biggest challenge in data engineering today.
And catalog engineering is the most important thing
you will have for an organization.
Luckily for us,
as data people, there's been a recent very, very large
push towards open table formats, open standards for this kind of thing.
So what we're seeing now is you now have an overarching catalog that sits
on the federation layer that where you apply your governance and policy.
I'm in the
Iceberg world, which is primarily where I come from.
These things are pushed by Databricks and Snowflake for Apache Polaris.
And yeah, so and these are very, very fast moving or
well maintained projects that are trying to swallow as much of that governance
and policy that they can apply across as many of the data layers as you can.
Obviously, if you're a huge data provider
like Databricks, is in your best interest to solve this problem.
And I'm really, really happy that they are taking the interest
and solving this problem. Now,
one quick note on Federation, though,
in terms of safety,
almost every single approach that I've seen to federation,
including the Streambased approach,
will go through the public advertised route to the underlying data system.
So we don't carve a special route,
down.
So you inherit governance policies and,
and everything that you need from that route in.
It's not perfect, but
but you do you do inherit quite a lot of safety
from the underlying system by going the Federation route.
Just going with the ROI theme for a second.
What would you say?
I suppose first, in terms of general principles,
but then feel free to talk about things that Streambased do on this
that helps you measure the marginal value of adding
more data sources so that you know the additional visibility.
You're actually kind of verifying that
you're getting better outcomes rather than,
you know, it's starting to actually create too much complexity or noise.
Yeah.
I thought you were going to ask me the performance question.
So I thought you were going to ask me how we measure the the cost of data access.
A bad data access? That one's easy.
Your Snowflake query cost you like $1,200.
Yeah. So.
But yes, you're talking about the availability, the extra scope of data.
Yeah, I don't know.
I'm not even
going to pretend it's very, very difficult to.
That's a metric that is so, so difficult to measure it.
So how do you it's so subjective.
How do you,
value the increase the quality of your
yeah.
How do you put a number on the increased quality of your answers?
Because it was able to look at a wider data scope.
If you do have a solution, I'd love to know it.
Yeah.
It's, it's something we've hit up against with multiple customers.
And it's very.
I'm, I'm, I'm on live stream,
so I shouldn't really say this, but I'll be honest with you.
What we tend to do in that situation is we back away from that one and go
look at how much money we're saving you in Snowflake, right?
Rather than the
opportunity
benefit in ROI, we go, look, here's the
it's saving you costs on your existing workload.
I would love to solve that problem.
On that note, thank you so much.